)mitrii **Maksimov**

Erlangen, Germany

📕+49 15203762106 | 💌 maksimov.dmitry.m@gmail.com | 🖸 Maksimov-Dmitry | 🛅 Maksimov-Dmitry | 💆 maksimov.dmitry.m | 💃 dmitrymaksimov

Summary

3+ years of diverse data science experience with specialties in market research, data visualization, market optimization and model lifecycle. 2+ years of diverse data/software engineering experience with specialties in pipelines integration, architecure design using AWS, database maintenance and deployment.

1+ years of diverse machine learning engineering with a focus on model management and deployment.

In addition, while studying at the university and various courses(e.g. MADE from VK), I learned many skills like: NLP, LLM, Reinforcement Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Pytorch, Transformers, Huggingface, PyTorch Lightning, Optimization, Spark, Hadoop, Scala, Recommender Systems, kubernetes, algorithms, A/B testing and data structures.

Love to share knowledge with different communities. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for various tasks and learning new technologies and tools.

Skills_

MLOps AWS, Docker, GitHub, Retool, Linux, Bash, REST API, Google Cloud, CI/CD, MLflow, AimStack, Hydra, Vertex AI

Statistical Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Probability Theory, XGBoost, PyTorch, scikit-learn, ETL, Vertica, Search Engine **ML/Data Science**

Optimization, PostgreSQL, Market Research, Parsing, Streamlit

Programming Python, SQL, SAS base Languages Russian, English, German

Work Experience _____

T.C.R. International

DATA/SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sep. 2021 - Present

- Developed and maintained processes for financial systems, with 90% of the processes developed with my active participation
- · Optimized airflow dags and configuration which allowed reducing the cost of the astronomer by 70%
- · Investigated strategies and solutions to reduce AWS infrastructure costs, optimizing resource allocation and usage
- Maintained the infrastructure, specifically working with AWS S3 and RDS
- Developed several AWS Lambda functions for automation and streamlined processing
- · Created a Deep Learning trading algorithm to optimize trading strategies and predict market movements
- Implemented processes for maintaining an extensive internal symbology database consisting of over 30,000 symbols
- Stack: Python, AWS (S3, RDS, Lambda), Airflow, PostgreSQL, Retool, REST API, Docker, CI/CD, PyTorch, XGBoost, AimStack, Hydra, Blankly(backtesting)

GFK Nuremberg, Germany

DATA SCIENTIST/MLOPS & WORK STUDY

- Apr. 2022 Oct. 2023 · Creating a tool to compare segmentations and their impact on the market
- Developing a method to detect AoI(areas of interests)
- · Investigating cannibalisation effects
- Evaluating competitors algorithm
- · Maintained the CI/CD pipeline
- Migrated a Deep Learning model to Vertex AI on Google Cloud
- Stack: Python, Google Cloud Platform, Streamlit, PostgreSQL, Vertex AI, CI/CD

SDVOR Moscow, Russia

DATA SCIENTIST Apr. 2020 - Jan. 2022

- · Creating an attribution model in advertising for SDVOR site using Markov chain as a result advertising costs decreased by 5%
- Programming ETL workflows for competitors site's parsing
- · Building service to optimize price for sales using SAS, python, SQL, which increased the profit on some products by 10%
- · Accomplishing computer vision model to compare planorgam and realogram via photo in a shop
- Creating telegram-bot as a server for different tasks
- Stack: Python, SAS, Vertica, PostgreSQL, Telegram API

Education

M.S. IN DATA SCIENCE Oct. 2021 - Present

 Developed Personalized Anomaly Detection Model based on continuous-time LSTM and Bayesian Decision Theory. Stack: Pytorch, Aim-Stack/MLFlow, Hydra

BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

Moscow, Russia

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2020 - Jun. 2021

• Finished 1 semester

BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

Moscow, Russia

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

• GPA - 4.42, max - 5.0

Extracurricular Activity

MADE at VK

Moscow, Russia

STUDENT Sep. 2022 - Jun. 2023

- · Gained expertise in different areas of ML (e.g. NLP, DL, Computer Vision, MLOps, basic ML, Python, ML in BigData, etc)
- Core member in a project to create a recommendation system for articles' authors
- Core member in a project to create a User Request-Based Fake Web Document Text Generation system

ML at Mail.ru Group

Moscow, Russia

STUDENT

Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

· Gained knowledge in basic ML

Certificates

Aug. 2023 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS

Jun. 2023 MADE Big Data Academy. Machine Learning Engineer, VK

405-67419

Oct. 2022 Completion of the Deep Learning Exercise, FAU

Mar. 2020 Labeled data learning, Coursera

Mar. 2020 Math and Python for data analysis, Coursera

2019 C/C++, Mail.ru Group

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL AWARDS

Jan. 2023 **8th Place**, Tensor Tournament

Erlangen, Germany

Oct. 2022 **2nd Place**, Classification of Solar Cell Defects

Erlangen, Germany

DOMESTIC AWARDS

2021 **1st Place**, SDVOR Hacking Competition

Tyumen, Russia